Emmanuel Atama

Junior Software Developer Git Hub

<u>Links</u>

M: +447951544599 <u>LinkedIn</u>

E: emmanuelatama@outlook.com Portfolio

Personal Summary

Have a good and practical knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, Typescript, Bootstrap 5, PHP, PhpMyAdmin, OutSystems, Docker, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Node.js, MongoDB, Design sprints and Agile Software Development.

Before graduating from Boolean UK in January 2022, I worked as a substitute teacher (cover supervisor) across schools in the west midlands. My desire to merge science with a programming language to create an interactive online classroom prompted my career change into IT as a software developer.

Possess a positive mental attitude, organised and self-motivated, and always willing to learn new skills. A very good and reliable team player and can easily adapt to any situation.

Education & Qualifications

- Full stack Software Development at Boolean UK 2022
- IGCSE English 2019
- MSc Renewable Energy and Resource Management at University of South
 Wales 2015
- BEng Mechanical Engineering at University of agriculture Makurdi, Nigeria –
 2013



Programming Skills

Front end – HTML5, CSS3, React, Typescript (Ts), JavaScript (Js), C#, PHP

Back end – JavaScript (Js), Typescript (Ts), Node

Database – PostgreSQL, MySQL, Prisma Schema (ORM)

DevOps – OutSystems Reactive

Others – Bootstrap5, Docker, Git, GitHub



Project Experience

Perfect Match Dating Site

- Using React for the front end, Node with typescript for the back end, PostgreSQL and Prisma schema for the database. I was able to create a dating site that uses JWT to secure the registration and signing of users to the web application.
- For more details, please visit my GitHub repo

Community Project - Christ Church Birmingham

- Used a blank template provided by the <u>Hubb</u> to finish the building of a church website that can be viewed across all platforms with responsiveness.
- To view the finished work, please click the link <u>CCB</u>

Wordle Duplicate

- Used React to build an online word game which is similar to wordle.
- For more details, visit the finished work here Wordle Duplicate



Part Time T-Level Code Instructor with Walsall Studio School via TeacherActive, UK

Sept 2022 - Till Date

- Supported the ICT teacher in delivering the T- Level technical qualification in Production, Design and Development to year 12 – year 13 students in accordance with the Pearson specifications.
- Delivered the basics and foundation of python programming language to year
 students.
- Supported the ICT department in finding placement for the year 12 & 13 students (current on-going).

Part Time Substitute Teacher / Cover Supervisor with Teacher Active, UK

Jan 2022 - Till Date

 General cover for science and math ranging from year 7 – year 11, and sixth form.

Student Coding Bootcamp with Boolean UK

June 2021 – Jan 2022

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, PHP
- Back-end: Node (Express), Typescript, Postgres, MySQL, Prisma Schema (ORM)

Cover Supervisor with Teacher Active, UK

April 2021 – June 2021

Cover Supervisor with First for Education, UK

April 2020 – June 2021

SEN Instructor / Offsite Tutor with St Paul's Community Development Trust, UK

April 2019 – Feb 2020

- Delivered Functional skills Math Level 2 & 3 to the pupils and prep them for their exams.
- Also delivered BTEC Science Level 2 & 3 by launching the module briefs and supported the pupils to achieve the required task while meeting up with the subject requirements.

Cover Supervisor with Connex Education, September 2018 – April 2019
Intervention Tutor with Waverley School, April 2018 – September 2018
Leave To Remain application to home office, Jan 2018 – March 2018
Cover Supervisor with First for Education, April 2020 – June 2021
Exam Invigilator with Malet Lambert School, Jan 2017 – March 2017
Support Worker with Victory Social Care, Feb 2016 – January 2017

Skills

- Analytical and problem-solving skills
- Communication skills
- Team Player

Courses

- January 2022 Learning Design Sprints, LinkedIn Learning
- January 2022 Agile Software Development: Creating an Agile Culture, LinkedIn Learning.

- January 2022 Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), LinkedIn Learning.
- January 2022 Microservices Foundation, LinkedIn Learning
- June 2021 OutSystems Reactive for Beginners, *Udemy*

References - References are available upon request.